SEBASTIEN VASEY

(+1) $617\,388\,5103$ • vasey.sebastien@gmail.com • svasey.github.io

SUMMARY

Mathematician and computer scientist. 10+ years of experience researching and solving complex problems in theoretical mathematics. Generally enjoys navigating and building elaborate systems, working out abstract and concrete problems, and implementing solutions. Experienced with machine learning, programming, and system administration. Detailed knowledge of the foundations of computer science. Extensive public speaking experience.

EXPERIENCE

Harvard University

July 2017-June 2020

Benjamin Peirce fellow in mathematics

- Pure research: Solved open problems in mathematical logic. Published 34 peer-reviewed articles (half with collaborators in the US and abroad). Gave numerous talks at seminars and international conferences. Refereed for ten journals.
- Applied research: Data science collaboration with Hossein Estiri at Massachusetts General Hospital.
 Developed machine learning methods to estimate plausibility of diagnoses in electronic health records.
- Teaching: Nine classes in mathematics, at all university levels, with class sizes between 5 and 40.
 Instant transition to remote teaching during the COVID-19 crisis. Supervised undergraduate student research projects. Three teaching awards.
- **Services:** Active member of mathematics department committees: graduate qualifying exam, intensive undergraduate advising, graduate admission.

Global Card SA (Geneva)

Aug. 2008-Jan. 2009

System programmer

- Development: Within a small team, developed from the ground up a networked access control system enabling people to unlock doors using their smartphone (via bluetooth).
- System administration: Monitored and maintained all the company's linux servers.

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University

M.Sc. and Ph.D. in Mathematical Sciences (2011-2017)

Sacks Prize for best thesis in logic worldwide and Guy C. Berry award for best thesis in Science at CMU.

Swiss Federal Institute of Technology (EPFL)

B.Sc. in Communication Systems (2008-2011)

Ranked first out of 27 students. GPA: 5.74/6

SKILLS

Programming Languages Operating Systems and Tools Mathematics and CS

Scala, Java, C, C++, Python, Haskell.

Linux system administration, free software tools like Emacs and Git. Foundations of software, algorithms, probability, machine learning.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages Citizenships French (native), English (fluent), German (intermediate). US permanent resident. French and Swiss citizen.